Guide to the Karl P. Cohen papers M1798
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- 8. subject files
  - 31. NUEXCO, 1987-1996
    - reports, July-December, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - reports, January-June, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - reports, July-December, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - reports, January-December, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - reports [incomplete], 1995-1996 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 32. Oak Ridge Gaseous Diffusion Plant (ORGDP), 1968-1981 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - 33. Plutonium (Pu) Denaturing, 1977-2000 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - 34. proliferation
    - general, 1949-1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - AEC, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Arms Control and Disarmament Agency Meeting, 1973-12-12 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - articles, reports, etc., 1977-1983 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - articles, reports, papers, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Nuclear Connection (Oak Ridge Study) paper correspondence, 1984 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Nuclear Connection project correspondence. Washington, D.C., 1984 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - The Front End of the Fuel Cycle. KPC (IEA Nuclear Connection project), 1984 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Pre-1983 KPC, 1978-1984 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Pre-83 Others (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - 35. radiation, 1972-1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 36. Reason Foundation - privatization study
    - material, 1978-1988 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Assignment, 1987-1988 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Guides - Think Piece (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - 37. reports, miscellaneous
    - Anderson Rep. [?] - Nuexco Report 1984, Tricastin Project Report 1979 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Reactor Orders, 1974-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Ford Foundation report, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - misc. (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - 38. safety
    - Reactor Safety, 1972-1982 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Safety History, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Safety History - Cohen (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 39. Scientists and Engineers for Secure Energy, Inc. (SE2)
    Scientists and Engineers for Secure Energy
    - SE2, 1981 (Box 36, Folder 2, Box 39, Folder 3, Box 47, Folder 7)
    - report (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Statements, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Billing, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Committee on Regulatory Assessment, 1982-1983 (Box 49, Folder 3, Folder 2)
    - Current Opinion 84-85 - Scientists and Engineers for Secure Energy, Inc. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Current Opinion 84-85 [articles, papers, reports], 1982-1986 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - 40. Sweden [brochures] (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - 41. Thorium, 1975-1978 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - 42. Three Mile Island
    Three Mile Island Nuclear Power Plant (Pa.)
    - TMI, 1978-1993 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Nuclear Safety Analysis Center (NSAC) Analysis report, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Kemeny Report, etc., 1979-1980 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - 43. USSR, 1971-1973 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - 44. waste, 1975-1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 45. Waste Isolation Pilot Plant (WIPP), 1978-1982 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - 46. U.S. Department of Energy (DOE)
    United States. Department of Energy
    - U.S. Policies, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Uranium Enrichment Annual Reports, 1979-1986 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Updates - Nuclear Power Program Information and Data, 1980-1982 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Updates - Nuclear Power Program Information and Data, 1982-1983 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Updates - Nuclear Power Program Information and Data, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 1)
- 9. Columbia University textbooks & notebooks, 1930s
  - Analytical Dynamics / [Wills?], 1933 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Continuous Geometry / Von Neumann, 1936 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Continuous Groups / Weyl, 1935 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Electromagnetics 1&2 / Quimby, 1934-1935 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Functional Operators Vol.I / Von Neumann, 1935 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Functional Operators Vol.II / Von Neumann, 1935 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Mathematical Statistics / Wilks, 1943 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Theory of Invariants / Weyl, 1936 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Theory of Positron / Pauli, 1936 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Electromagnetics notebook, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Analysis III, IV, V notebooks, 1934-35 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Physics/Chemistry notebooks, 1933-1934 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Optics notebook, 1930s (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Function Theory notebooks, 1930 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Research notebook, 1934 (Box 57, Folder 4)
- 10. consulting, misc.
  - Consulting Agreements, Planning, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Business, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Universities, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - misc. expense reports, 1978-1987 (Box 51, Folder 8)
- 11. reprints
  - Isotope Separation / Coop. Phenom., 1931-1964 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Isotope Separation -Theory, 1958-1981 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - KPC [Cohen], HCU [Urey] And Others, 1937-1963 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Solvent Action on Optical Rotary Power [Cohen, etc.], 1940 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Foreign, 1973-1992 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - RMP (Reviews of Modern Physics) Specials, 1975-1985; 6 issue(s) (Box 43, Folder 2)
- 12. mementos
  - Mementos (Box 16, Folder 3, Box 60)
    Souvenirs such as commemorative paperweights, plates and ashtrays, Cohen's customized hard hat, nametag, etc. Most are from General Electric. Box 60 is all objects.
  - awards and certificates of recognition from the ANS, California Society of Professional Engineers, and G.E. (Box 61)
  - ANS Presidential Year Scrapbook items, 1968-1969 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    Items removed from scrapbook. Includes photographs, clippings from Nuclear News, conference programs, and correspondence.
- 13. photographs and slides
  - family photographs, circa 1920s (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Eastman plates [graphs and equations], circa 1920s-1930s (Box 59, Card-box 5, Card-box 4)
  - Atomic Energy Commission photograph [document signing ceremony, early to mid-1950s] (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - slides - 4/26/77 Speech; 11/8/77 Speech [autobiographical presentations; at least one image is a copy of a print in "Family Photos"], 1977 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - slides - numbered for presentations (Box 59, Folder 4, Folder 5)
  - slide box - 1) Aix. M. Cohen. Session III [presentation slides] (Box 59, Card-box 1)
  - slide box - After 23. Blackboard [presentation slides] (Box 59, Card-box 2)
  - slide box (metal Kodak case) [presentation slides] (Box 59, Card-box 3)
- 14. audio and video
  - Karl P. Cohen Interview by Dr. Clarence Larson. Pioneers of Science and Technology Historical Association, 1988-03-29; 1 videotape(s) (Box 59, Videotape 1)
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Digital copy available.
  - video interview documentation [copied from correspondence series] (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Karl Cohen, 1 audiocassette(s) (Ampex 60 min.) (Box 59, Audiocassette 1)
  - C,R & D. Side #1 Only, 1980-01-30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Scotch AVC-120) (Box 59, Audiocassette 2)